Alexander Wu

0415 182 909 | alexwu7583@gmail.com.au | Artarmon, NSW 2064

Portfolio https://alex0n0.github.io/portfolio

GitHub https://github.com/alex0n0?tab=stars

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexander-wu-149372194

Summary

Full-Stack Web Developer with a background in information systems. A graduate of The Coding Bootcamp at the University of Sydney with the technical skills to efficiently turn designs into responsive front-end code connected to API servers using either SQL or noSQL databases. Quick at understanding new concepts and enjoy sharing these findings with colleagues. Praised for writing readable code across multiple team projects. Recently completed an internship at a VR startup targeted at heavy machinery usage and health and safety training. Primary focus is to become a developer who is capable across requirements gathering, design and development.

Skills (Tools | *Libraries*)

Front End HTML5, CSS6 (css variables, flex and grid layouts), Sass, JS, TS, jQuery, *Bootstrap*,

Materialize, Data visualisation (Chart.js), React, Angular

Back End Consuming/creating RESTful APIs and web servers (Node.js, *Express.js*, C#),

Handlebars.js, SQL (MySQL, SQLite, Mysql.js, Sequelize, Microsoft Sequel Server, LINQ), noSQL (MongoDB, Mongo.js, Mongoose.js), Google APIs (Maps, Analytics),

Testing (Mocha, Chai)

Others Git, Sourcetree, Jira, Photoshop

Projects

"OrderAway" - React Application with User Accounts

Dec 2019

(Demo: https://beanstalk03.herokuapp.com/ | Code: https://github.com/alex0n0/OrderAway) Individual project of a SaaS application for restaurants with account creation and multiple user interfaces for business, kitchen and customer actions.

"Clicker Game" - Single Page React Application

Dec 2019

(Demo: https://beanstalk88.herokuapp.com/ | Code: https://github.com/alex0n0/reactclickergame)
A memory based React.js clicker game with a Batman theme that randomises options and tracks current and high scores.

"ChowTown" – HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap Application Sep 2019

(Demo: https://elliloes.github.io/Project-ChowTown | Code: https://github.com/ElliLoes/Project-ChowTown)

A web application for searching, saving and organising collections of favourite restaurants around the world to encourage exploration of more dining options locally and internationally. Includes the use of Google location API and browser local storage. Group project with complete front-end design process, agile scrum methodology and experience integrating front and back end components.

"Star Wars RPG" – HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap Application

Aug 2019

(Demo: https://alex0n0.github.io/Star-Wars-RPG-Game | Code: https://github.com/alex0n0/Star-Wars-RPG-Game)

"One vs all"—style game with a continuously changing UI and designed with consideration of UX shown in elements like semantically colored zones and disabled buttons depending on the game phase.

Work Experience

Material Creator

Mar 2016 - present

Edupia

Creating workbooks and trial papers for students, distributing workload of a project to smaller groups for faster work flow. Designing various utility tools such as interactive marking forms in Excel. Formatting materials for upload to database.

Internship

Full Stack Developer

Mar 2020 - present

Achievr

Working on designing and creating the company website through a CMS with the addition of custom made components, contributing to the C# API backend and Angular client dashboard to show service usage data. Refactored the structure of the CSS in the Angular site for ease of maintenance.

Education

The Coding Bootcamp at the University of Sydney

Full Stack Web Developer Bootcamp Certificate

July 2019 - Jan 2020

University of New South Wales

Mar 2015 - Aug 2019

Bachelor of Commerce/Information Systems